謝謝各位
Thank you. Thank you.
也給你們自己點掌聲, 因為是你們付出的努力
But no, give yourselves a hand because it was your hard work
讓這個機構旗下的Yardsham Inlet邁進最成功的一年
that gave Yardsham Inlet the best year in the history of this agency.
在我們將功勞拱手相讓給我們的上司前
Before we let all that success go to our heads,
我們想讓大家來個聚會, 並再記起
we just thought we should get together
and reconnect with the fundamentals
是甚麼帶我們來到這一步
of what actually got us here.
為此, 我將會交給
For that, I'm gonna turn it over
我們產品的創辦人, 詩人及哲學家
to our resident poet philosopher of product.
反叛的指標
The rebel command of brand.
他是位讓麥迪遜大道的人聞風喪膽的領袖
He's the guru who terrifies Madison Avenue.
我的拍檔及知己
My partner, my better half,
Howard Inlet
Howard Inlet.
愛你
Love you.
噢, 你的"原因"是甚麼?
Oh. What is your "why"?
你今早為甚麼起床?
Why did you even get out of the bed this morning?
你為甚麼吃你所吃的?
Why did you eat what you ate?
你為甚麼穿你所穿的?
Why did you wear what you wore?
你為甚麼來這裡?
Why did you come here?
除了因為我會找人替代你的位置
Other than the fact that I would fire you and hire someone else
如果你不上班的話, 但...
if you didn't show up for work, but...
我要說的不是這個, 更重大的"原因"
Not that. The big "why."
我們會來這裡工作絕對不是為了賣東西而已
We're certainly not here to just sell shit.
我們來這裡
We are here
是去連繫
to connect.
生命的重點是人們
Life is about people.
而廣告的重點是
Advertising is about
點明我們的產品和服務
illuminating how our products and services
能夠提升人們生活的質素
will improve people's lives.
那
Now,
我們如何辦到?
how do we do that?
愛情
Love.
時間
Time.
死亡
Death.
這三個抽象的概念能夠連繫世上所有人
Now these three abstractions connect every single human being on Earth.
我們想要得到的事物
Everything that we covet,
我們害怕失去的事物
everything that we fear not having,
我們最終都會買的事物
everything that we ultimately end up buying
全都因為
is because at the end of the day
我們渴望愛情
we long for love,
我們希望有更多時間
we wish we had more time,
還有我們害怕死亡
and we fear death.
愛情
Love.
時間
Time.
死亡
Death.
我們就從那著手
Let's begin there.
[三年後]
這個砌了多久?
How long did this one take?
五天
Five days.
那其實很棒
That's pretty impressive.
- 可能他太早回來工作了   - 你開玩笑嗎?
- Maybe he came back too soon. - Are you kidding me?
這種日復一日的循例已經整整六個月了
It's been six months of this zombie routine.
我們不能再放縱他
We can't indulge this anymore.
尤其因為
Especially because
Danworth金融公司快要跟我們解約了
we're getting fired by Danworth Financial.
甚麼? 告訴我不是真的吧
What? You're kidding me.
- 不是吧, Whit   - 抱歉, 甚麼?
- No, Whit, come on!  - I'm sorry, what?
我昨天才跟他們會面
But I just talked to them yesterday.
我知道, 所有人都盡力隱瞞事實
I know. Everybody's been doing their best to cover,
但那整個戶口都是建基於Howard的人際關係
but that entire account is built on Howard's relationship.
我們一半的收入才是建基於Howard的人際關係
Half our billings are built on Howard's relationships.
這下可慘了, 簡直是大災難
This is a disaster. This is a disaster.
不, 還不是
No. Not yet.
宏盟集團向我們提出一股$17的提議 [美國一家公司]
We have an offer from Omnicom for $17 a share...
- 我們不能這樣做吧    - 但他們想要
- Oh, come on!    -...but they want an answer
- 在新年前得到答覆   - 殊
- by New Year's.   - Shh.
坦白說, 我們甚至不值一股$14
Let's be honest, we're not worth $14 a share
如果我的拍檔打算繼續
if my partner takes a sabbatical
在他幻想的瘋狂小鎮中以骨牌之王自冠
as the local domino champion of Crazy Town.
Whit, 那說得有點過份了
That's a little harsh, Whit.
抱歉, 但那是現實
I'm sorry, but it's true.
Simon, 我正式賦予你接受宏盟集團的提議的權力
Simon, I am empowering you. Go make the deal with Omnicom.
我也想, 但Howard手持有表決權股份
I wish I could, but Howard controls the voting shares.
我會跟Howard說, 好了嗎?
I'll deal with the Howard part, okay?
先準備文件草稿, Simon
Just push the papers, Simon.
我依然不明白為何Howard手持60%有表決權股份
I still don't understand why Howard got 60% of the voting shares
而你只擁有40%
and you only got 40.
因為我當時需要金錢去辦妥我的離婚手續
Because I needed cash to settle my divorce
而Howard讓我賣給他一些股份, 那幫了我很大的忙
and Howard did me a huge favor and let me sell him some.
即是說, 如果你從沒跟那剛入行的創作者有婚外情
So, if you never had an affair with some junior creative,
我們就不會落得如此下場?
we wouldn't be in this situation?
這是不準確又不公平的
Inaccurate and unfair
如果硬要讓我一力承擔
to put it squarely on my shoulders.
我只是在說事實
Well, I'm just pointing out the facts.
天啊, 有人會不喜歡這香氣嗎?
Oh, my God. Don't you just love that smell?
等下
Wait. Stop.
閉下眼
Close your eyes.
用力吸
Breathe it in.
有沒有讓你回想起童年?
Doesn't that remind you of your childhood?
Claire, 來這邊
Claire, come here.
坐下吧, 我有點事要告訴你
Come on, I got to tell you something.
甚麼?
What?
我最近一直試著改變我們現在的處境
I have been doing something about our situation
我覺得你有必要知道
that you need to know about.
你都做了甚麼?
What did you do?
我聘請了一個人
I hired someone.
你聘請了一個人?
You hired someone?
對, 聽著, 以前Eloise抓到我出軌
Yes. Look, when Eloise caught me cheating,
是因為她聘用了一位叫Sally Price的私家偵探
she used a private investigator named Sally Price.
她看上去像一個摩門教的老婆婆般不起眼
She's this woman who looks like a Mormon grandmother,
這給了她最好的隱藏身份
and it makes her very good at the whole stealth thing.
你聘請了那個讓你離婚的女人?
You hired the woman who caused your divorce?
不, 是我導致離婚的
No. I caused my divorce.
Sally Price只是將我的婚外情記錄在案而已
Sally Price just documented it.
你還真不計前嫌
Wow. That was actually enlightened.
我們早已討論過吧, 我是個有深度的人
I have hidden depth. We've discussed this.
所以
So,
你為何聘用那個摩門教老婆婆?
why did you hire the Mormon grandmother?
因為我們需要記錄Howard現在的情況
Because we need to document what's going on with Howard.
我們需要顯示他精神不夠健全去作出決定
We need to show that he's not mentally fit to vote his shares.
不, 我們不是真的要...
No. We're not really in that place where we're...
我們真的要變成這樣的損友嗎?
We're actually gonna be the people who would do that to a friend?
不是因為他一定不會賣他的股份
It's not that he won't sell,
而是因為他甚至不去談論這個問題
it's that he won't even have a conversation about selling.
我試過接觸他, 跟他說話
I try to talk to him, I try to reach him,
而那就好像我跟他處在不同的次元一樣
and it's like I'm not even in the same physical space with him.
他心不在焉
He's not there.
他的孩子去世了
His kid died.
那已經是兩年前的事了, Claire
That was two years ago, Claire.
我們要怎樣...
What are we gonna...
現在火燒眉毛
This is our lives at stake.
我們不再是小孩了, 你當著我面跟我說
We're not kids anymore. You look me in the face
你願意讓過去十年你所付出過的
and tell me that you're willing to have everything you've worked for
付諸東流, 我就不去做
for the last 10 years just evaporate.
這個私家偵探出色嗎?
Is this PI good?
她抓到我出軌了
She caught me cheating.
Oscar也能做到
Oscar could have caught you cheating.
誰是Oscar?
Who the hell's Oscar?
我兒子
My son.
噢, 那個Oscar?
Oh. That Oscar?
這個私家偵探不會找到任何
This private investigator isn't gonna find anything
違背道德的事
that'll pass for moral turpitude.
至少不會在Howard身上找到
Not on Howard,
但如果她能引起他的法律資格的質疑
but if she can raise concern regarding legal capacity,
那我們就成事了
then we'll be in business.
我真的覺得我們別無選擇
I do really think that we are out of other options.
他六個月來一直對心理輔導員愛理不理
You know, he terrorized the grief counselor for six months.
他完全不理我們遠道從秘魯取回來的死藤水薩滿草藥
He totally blew off the Ayahuasca shaman we flew in all the way from Peru.
而我們完全不能開解他
And our...Our intervention was a disaster.
我只是...
I just...
你的提議聽起來不對
Look, uh, this doesn't feel right.
我明白
I know.
但從一個六歲的孩子患上絕症開始
But when something starts with a six-year-old dying,
沒甚麼聽起來是對的
nothing is gonna feel right.
他寫了幾封信
He writes letters.
信? 甚麼信?
Letters? What kind of letters?
這可能是我生涯遇過最奇怪的一件事
This might be the strangest thing I have ever come across.
- 你有拿到那些信嗎?   - 有
- You got the letters?   - Oh, yeah.
我們可以問下來歷嗎?
Can we ask you how?
花了我$800
Cost me $800
來造這把鑰匙
to get this cut.
順道說下
And just so you know,
從郵箱裡直接偷取信件是犯法的
it's a federal offense to steal mail directly from a mailbox.
- 你可以收起...   - 對
- You could...   - Yeah.
- 共有三封信   - 寫給誰的?
- So, three letters.   - Who are they to?
- 噢, 不是"誰"   - 甚麼意思?
- Oh, not who.   - What do you mean?
Howard不寫信給人
Howard doesn't write letters to people.
他寫信給事
He writes to things.
- 甚麼事?   - 時間
- What kind of things?   - Time.
愛情
Love.
死亡
Death.
那三個抽像的概念
The three abstractions.
致時間
"Time,
人們說你是一切傷害的良藥
"they say you heal all wounds,
但他們不會說起你如何
"but they don't talk about how you destroy
將一切美好化為腐朽
"all that's good in the world.
如何將美麗的事物化作塵埃
"How you turn beauty into ash.
聽著, 你對我來說只不過是木化石
"Well, you're nothing more than petrified wood to me.
你是塊不會分解的壞死組織
"You're a dead tissue that won't decompose.
你甚麼也不是
"You're nothing."
那不代表甚麼, 我們不能利用這個吧?
That doesn't prove anything. We can't use that, right?
對, 孩子們都寫信給聖誕老人
No. I mean, kids write letters to Santa Claus,
那不代表他們瘋了
it doesn't mean they're crazy.
不, 這很治療
No. This is therapeutic.
太悲傷了
It's so sad.
對, 還有甚麼嗎?
Yeah. Anything else?
他平常下班後, 會到布魯克林的一個寵物公園
Usually after work, he goes to a small dog park in Brooklyn,
即使他沒有養狗
even though he doesn't own a dog.
就呆坐在那裡
Just sits there for hours.
他會寫信給狗嗎?
Does he write letters to the dogs?
你開玩笑嗎?
Are you serious?
我說, 那就是我們想要的全壘打, 對吧?
Well, that would be like the home run, right?
那是我們想要的有力證據
I mean, that's what we need.
- 他會嗎?   - 我沒有看到
- Does he?   - Not that I saw.
- 好吧, 還有甚麼嗎?   - 沒有了, 真的
- Okay. What else?   - That's it, really.
每天回到自己的寓所, 非必要也不出門
Goes home to his apartment. Rarely leaves before morning.
沒有網絡, 寬頻, 電話, 甚麼也沒有
No Wi-Fi, cable, phone. Nothing.
你是塊不會分解的壞死組織
"You're a dead tissue that won't decompose."
Howard?
嗨, 是Claire
Hey, it's Claire.
我經過路口的一間餐廳給你買了晚餐
I swung by that place down the street and got you some dinner.
有你喜歡的蝦
It's that shrimp thing you like.
好吧, 我把它放在這, 以防你還沒吃晚餐
Okay, I'm gonna leave it right here, in case you haven't eaten.
嘿, 別再留下食物在那裡
Hey, don't keep leaving the food there.
他不會吃的
He doesn't eat it.
噢, 抱歉
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
還有他又遲了交房租
And he's late on his rent again.
他不應門, 我也沒有手提電話號碼給他
He doesn't answer his door, and I don't have a working number for him.
他沒有電話了
Yeah, he doesn't have a phone anymore.
他欠多少錢了? 我寫支票給你
Um, how much does he owe? I'll write you a check.
隨便你
If that's what you want to do.
還有如果你不帶走那晚餐
And, uh, if you're not doing anything with that shrimp...
我想說上週的球花甘藍很美味
Broccoli rabe last week was delicious.
他來了
Here he is.
嘿, 你的行李呢?
Hey, where's your stuff?
我本想發訊息給你, 但媽媽要我致電給你
I wanted to text you, but Mom said I had to call.
說甚麼?
Text me about what?
然後Barry就我必須親口跟你說
But then Barry said I had to tell you in person.
所以我們現在都要聽Barry的提議嗎?
Are we taking life advice from Barry now?
你...你想告訴我甚麼?
What are... What are you trying to tell me?
我不會過來跟你住
I'm not coming to stay with you.
我要跟Barry和媽媽一起去巴哈馬
I'm going with Barry and Mom to the Bahamas.
不, 等下
No, no. Wait, wait, wait.
午安
Hi.
你好嗎?
How you doing?
我可以跟我的女兒
Can I get, like, five minutes, maybe a couple feet
獨自相處一會嗎?
just to have this conversation with my daughter?
謝謝
Thanks.
寶貝, 我...
Honey, I got...
我把所有事都計劃好了
I got all kinds of stuff planned.
我買了聖誕樹
I got a Christmas tree for us.
那你真慘
Then sucks for you.
我買了漢密爾頓音樂劇的票
I got us tickets to Hamilton.
那真糟糕
Then sucks for Hamilton.
Allison, 那音樂劇一票難求
That's a tough ticket, Allison.
我已經看過了
I've already seen it.
你看過? 跟你母親和Barry?
You did? You saw that with Mom and Barry?
和Odell Beckham Jr [美式足球外接手]
And Odell Beckham Jr.
還有Odell Beckham?
And Odell Beckham?
對
Yeah.
他是Barry的朋友之一
He's one of Barry's friends.
為甚麼?
Why?
為甚麼你不想跟我一起過節日?
Why don't you want to spend the holiday with me?
我想你了
I miss you.
因為我恨你
Because I hate you.
因為是個慈善家
Because you're a philanthropist.
因為你傷透了媽媽的心
Because you broke Mom's heart.
- 隨性所欲的人   - 甚麼?
- Philanderer.   - What?
你想說的是隨性所欲的人, 不是慈悲家,
The word you're looking for is philanderer, not philanthropist.
兩者有點不同
They have a slightly different meaning.
你當然知道分別
Well, you would know.
我答應他們親口告訴你, 現在我做到了
Look, I agreed to tell you in person, and now I have.
嘿
Hey,
祝你聖誕快樂
have a good Christmas.
等下
Hold it.
嗨
Hey.
趁你在, 來個快問快答嗎?
So, rapid fire round while I got you?
騎士隊作客
Cavs are in town.
在麥迪遜廣場花園上演聖誕大戰
Christmas showdown at the Garden.
我從沒給過你門票
I never give your seat away.
現在只剩我一個去, 但我們也可以一起去
I just go solo, but we could go.
到時候不理會大家也行
Don't even have to talk. Don't even have to look at each other.
可以像我們現在一樣, 然後專心看比賽
We can do just what we're doing right now and just watch the game.
就像舊時候一樣
Be like old times.
好了, 第二題
Right, number two.
我們快要失去Danworth這個客戶
We're gonna lose the Danworth account
因為那一直都是你打理的
because that's always been your relationship.
你也能想像得到, 他們不再感受到你的用心
And they're not feeling the love, as you might imagine.
所以那就是無可避免的
So that's gonna happen.
隨便吧
Whatever though,
因為我們有來自宏盟集團的提議, 而且非常誘人
because we've got an offer from Omnicom, and it's real.
一股$17
17 bucks a share.
請認真考慮, 因為...
Please consider it, because...
對, 我也知道
Yeah, yeah.
因為他們讓我們繼續現有的模式, 而且沒人會被辭退
Because they leave total creative control
and they let everybody keep their jobs,
我知道你在意你的員工, 因為你愛他們
which I know you care about, because you love these people.
非常愉快的談心
Good talk.
[找尋你的精子捐贈者]
[是時候擴大你的家庭]
北京的人來了
The Beijing boys are here.
天啊, 沒有人會想要喝中國咖啡
Oh, God. No one wants Chinese coffee.
我們總要為他們賣廣告
Well, we're selling it.
滿州的瑪琪雅朵咖啡, 嗯
The Manchurian macchiato. Mmm.
我們在為甚麼選角?
What are we casting?
- 遊輪   - 看, 那才值得
- Cruise line.    - Now, see, that's good copy.
放下一切, 尋找意義
"Shed your skin, find your life."
抱歉, 應該是
Sorry, it's
當你放下一切才能找到生命意義
"Life is found when you shed your skin."
- 有所謂嗎?   - 有, 因為是我寫的
- Does it really matter?  - Yes, because I wrote it.
原來如此, 但我的較好
Oh, well, my way's better.
- 你真認為嗎? 哪裡較好?   - 對
- Really? How?   - Yeah.
重溫一下, 你的是甚麼?
Well... Wait, what is your way?
當你放下一切才能找到生命意義
"Life is found when you shed your skin."
說中你腦裡想的
Which, you know, kind of hits you here.
放下一切, 尋找意義
"Shed your skin, find your life."
說到心窩裡
Hits you here.
真的耶
That does hit me here.
對吧?
Right?
你可以隨便拿去用
You can have it for free.
等下
Just, wait. Wait.
Wait.
- 嗨, Frankel   - 甚麼事?
- Hey, Frankel.   - Yeah?
放下一切, 尋找意義
"Shed your skin, find your life."
放下一切, 尋找意義, 知道了嗎?
Everybody, okay?
知道
Got it.
她美化了它
She made it better.
嘿!
Hey!
別走
No, no, no.
嘿!
Hey, hey!
而你用這樣的語氣跟我說話
"And you talk to me in such tones
說得好像不是我把你帶到這個世上
"as if it wasn't the breath in my lungs that gave you life."
- 你遲到了   - 抱歉
- You're late.   - Sorry.
說得好像不是因為我的靈光一觸
"As if it wasn't a spark in my mind
才給予生命意義
"that gave that life meaning."
噢, 你的舌頭在動, 你的嘴在吐字
"Oh, you move your tongue, you mouth syllables,
你的情感在翻騰
"you echo sentiment.
但你沒有活過
"But you do not breathe."
你說火花?
"You speak of spark?
那簡直是奢求
"That is richness.
因為你否認我們兩個之間的火花
"For you deny the spark between us all.
那火花比起你那冷酷無情的火燄, 簡直是太陽般溫暖
"A spark that is more a sun than the cold fire you claim.
而你竟形容我為年輕的衝動
"And you have called me a temporary madness.
一個邪惡的靈魂
"A vicious soul.
那
"Well,
撫心自問你想不想再見我一面
"then ask if you will see me just one more time."
你好
Hello?
Hi.
抱歉, 我擅自走進這裡
So sorry. I literally just wandered in,
我剛好看到最尾的部分
and I caught the tail end of that, and...
我可以表達我的讚賞嗎?
Can I just say that was beautiful?
那是甚麼話劇?
What is... What is it?
只是些構思而已
It's just something we're trying to put together.
我...我很喜歡話劇, 哪類型都喜歡
I just... I love theater. I see everything.
正式表演是甚麼時候? 我會來的
So when's opening night? I'll be there.
直到我們籌得足夠的錢前都不會有正式表演
There is no opening night until we get this money together.
- 你富有嗎?   - 我離婚了
- You rich?   - Divorced.
你從剛才試鏡就跟著我
You followed me from the casting session.
- 對, 是的   - 是吧
- Absolutely, I did. Yes.   - Yeah.
我幾乎看不到你, 但你的紅帽子幫了忙
I almost lost you, but the red hat helped.
我要說件有點突然的事
Hey, um, I'm gonna say something a little impulsive here,
聽起來或者有點瘋狂
maybe a little crazy,
我有件想要做的事
but, you know, I have something about to happen for me.
我正在跟別人商討當中, 但如果能成事
I'm in the middle of a deal that if it all comes together,
我就能資助你們
I'd be in a position to help.
那不是雙贏的局面嗎?
Well, now wouldn't that be lovely?
是, 是件很好的事
It would. Be great.
而你, 你剛才幫助了我
And you, you know, you fixed it.
所以, 如果你想要剛才試鏡的工作的話, 我們可以讓你來
So, we should get you back into casting if you want the gig.
抱歉, 我甚至還沒請教你的名字
Sorry, I don't even... I don't know your name.
- 我叫Amy   - Amy
- Amy.   - Amy.
好吧
Okay. Well,
我會再來的, Amy
I'll be back, Amy. I'll be back.
我先走...
Mmm. And I'll be...
抱歉
Hmm. Sorry.
我太興奮了
I was on the stage!
我會再來的
I'll be back.
你很有演技
You're good.
真有你的
Well done, you.
等下, 現在都有"犯罪現場:克里夫蘭"了嗎?
Wait, they have a CSI: Cleveland now?
是全新一輯
It's a new show.
那些狼人
The werewolves,
他們在外面聚集
they're meeting out front
每晚都是
all hours of the night.
對, 我也留意到
I heard them. Yeah.
我想他們...
I think they're...
我想他們正在投票選出組織的頭目
I think they're voting on a new head of the syndicate.
但
But
我有個浣熊朋友, 他是特種部隊的一員
I got a raccoon friend. He's on the task force.
他在外面幫我放了個監聽器在垃圾桶上
He put a bug out there for me by the trash cans.
我們將會錄下他們所說的一切
We're gonna tape everything they say
並以詐騙、操縱和賄賂組織法控告他們
and we'll bust them on a RICO statute.
我不知道那是甚麼
I don't know anything about that.
嘿, 我是你的兒子
Hey, I'm your son.
這我知道
I know that!
很好
Good.
我離開一下
I'll be right back.
我有個大膽的想法
Okay, I have kind of a wild idea.
你們聽了很可能會取笑我
And I know you're gonna laugh at me,
但記住我們沒有其他辦法, 所以聽我說完
but remember that we're desperate and hear me out.
我的母親自從中風後精神狀態就不佳, 對吧?
So, my mom hasn't been totally in her right mind since her stroke, right?
而我經常試著提醒她身邊發生甚麼事
And I'm always trying to remind her what's actually going on
還有改正她的胡言亂語
and correct the, sort of, daffy things that she says.
而這樣做令她感到不快樂, 我也不知所措
And it upsets her, and it really stresses me out.
有段時間事情變得很麻煩
And it was pretty much just awful for a while.
然後, 有人解開了我的心結
And then, someone said something very, very wise to me.
他們說: 或者你不該強逼她聽你的那套
They said, "Maybe you should stop trying to force your reality on her
而你試著跟她的思路走
"and just... Just go into her reality."
我以為你沒錢去支付治療費了
I thought you couldn't afford therapy anymore.
- 我是沒有, 那是我的優步司機說的  - 噢
- I can't. It was my Uber driver.   - Oh.
他完全正確
And he was totally right. Totally right!
當我開始照他說的做, 所有事都輕鬆多了
As soon as I started doing this,
everything got easier, you know?
我跟她的生活就變得很即興
Our life is like this improvisational game.
她說些有的沒的, 而我就以她的方式回答她
She just... She says wackadoodle stuff, and I respond to it.
現在她過得很快樂, 而我也頗喜歡這互動
And, uh, she's totally happy and I kind of have fun.
那讓我想到一個人
And that made me think of something else.
好了
Okay.
以前我在FBW時 [應為診所之類]
When I was at FBW,
我有個買興奮藥的戶口
I had this account for a psychostimulant drug, right?
他們辦了個甚麼籌款活動
And they went with some bullshit generic campaign,
我買了這套"西班牙裔美國人市場"
but I kept the Hispanic market.
看這個
Here, watch this. Okay.
那老師非常苦惱
So, the teacher is really stressing. He's saying, uh,
你們都在自己說話, 不聽我講課
"Well, you talk all the time! You never listen!"
然後怪物進來
And then here comes the monster.
它說: 不用這樣的
"It doesn't have to be this way."
老師說: 你是誰?
Teacher, "Who are you?"
怪物說: 我就是你的憤怒啊
Monster, "I'm your anger, man."
老師回答
And the teacher says...
我不能再忍受你, 你支配了我的生命
"I can't stand you, man. You dominate my life."
然後它回答: 有個解決方法, 朋友
And anger says, "There's a solution, my friend.
Docotrin, 助你解決憤怒問題
"Docotrin, say goodbye to your anger."
你明白我想說的話?
Do you see where I'm going with this?
- 不太懂   - 好了, 聽著
- Not really.   - Okay, okay. Look, look.
我們不能讓Howard聽我們的那套
We can't get Howard to deal with this
reality that we need him to deal with.
他在寫信給抽像的概念, 完全不合邏輯
And he's writing letters to abstractions which makes no sense.
但他依然繼續做
But... But he's doing it.
那麼, 如果我們跟他的思路
So, what if we just go into his reality
讓那些抽像的概念回應他?
and we get those abstractions to answer him?
抱歉, 我不明白
I'm sorry, I... I don't follow.
如果讓愛情, 時間, 死亡實體化
What if Love, Time and Death show up in person
回應Howard寫給他們的信怎樣?
and answer the letters that Howard's been writing to them?
在哪找愛情, 時間, 死亡?
How are Time, Love and Death gonna show up?
演員
Actors.
我們聘請演員扮演愛情, 時間, 死亡
We hire actors to be Love, Death and Time.
他們找到Howard並跟他對質
They find Howard and they confront him.
所以你想讓我們欺騙你的上司?
So, you want us to gaslight your boss?
- 抱歉, 甚麼?   - 煤氣燈下
- Huh? I'm sorry?   - Gas Light.
知道嗎? 是齣話劇, 然後拍成電影
You know? It was a play, then it was a movie.
那套煤氣燈下? 天啊
Gas Light? Oh, my God.
沒有人會再看長過八秒鐘的事了嗎?
Does nobody ever watch anything longer than eight seconds anymore?
她的意思是, 你想我們讓他以為自己瘋了?
What she's saying is you want us to make him think he's crazy?
不, 目的不是這個
No, no, no. It's not about making Howard think he's crazy.
Howard精神狀態不佳, 我們幾個都知道
Howard's not in a good mental state, and we know that.
目的是讓他人也知道
It's about underlining that fact so that other people can see it, too.
所以你想讓我們跟他接觸時演戲
Okay. So you want us to perform in this intervention,
而你們事後會資助我們的話劇?
and for that you're gonna finance our play?
- 對   - 正是
- That's it.   - Exactly.
對, 我們會資助這個甚麼...
Yeah, we'll finance whatever...
這看起來像是貨倉, 但...
I mean, this looks like a storage facility, but...
好吧, 其他演員, 我們怎樣?
Okay. Well, actors. What do we think?
- 不不不   - 噢, 不是
- No. No, no, no.   - Oh, no.
聽著
Listen, listen!
我們每人要求$15,000
We take $15,000 each.
- 好嗎? $15,000   - 你瘋了嗎?
- Okay? $15,000.  - Are you completely out of your mind?
好吧, 我們會幫你們
Okay, we'll do it.
以每人$20,000的報酬
$20,000, each.
不! 我剛...你們才剛說15,000, 我聽到的
Uh-uh! I just...You guys just said 15. I heard you say 15.
- 我喜歡20,000   - 我也是
- Mmm... I like 20.   - I like 20 as well.
20,000真的太...有點過份了
Well, 20's just... I don't know, it's a little steep.
我打算給2,000的, 這些人很可能住在布魯克林
I was thinking two. These guys probably live in Brooklyn.
- 他們月租$600   - 夠了, 停下吧
- They pay 600 bucks a month. - Stop talking. Just stop.
你做得不錯
You did a good job pulling them down.
這很可怕, 這事完全不對
This is horrible. This is completely wrong.
不, Amy, 這就是我們的工作, 是演戲
No, Amy. This is the work. This is acting.
你沒聽到他們說這個人的孩子過世了嗎?
Did you not hear them say that this man's lost his child?
有, 那就是為何他選擇向宇宙中尋找答案
Yes. And that's why he's reaching out to the cosmos for answers.
我們有幸扮演他想找的
Well, we get to be that cosmos.
所以你想我們運用這個男人的痛處, 然後怎樣?
So you want us to manipulate this guy's pain so that, what?
你們兌現? 賺很多錢?
What, you cash out?
You make a lot of money?
- 不!   - 當然不是!
- No!   - No, no, no, no!
你這樣說聽起來不對
That doesn't sound good when you put it that way.
- 這比看上去複雜得多   - 是嗎?
- It's a lot more complicated than that.  - Is it?
我們都愛這個人
We love this man.
他不只是我們上司, 他是朋友
And he's not just a boss, he's a friend.
Howard是個有才華, 創意和魅力的男人
Howard is a brilliant, creative, charismatic guy
他曾經是那樣無所畏懼
who used to be fearless.
他曾經熱愛他的生命, 而現在, 他恨透了生命
He used to love life, and right now, he hates it.
你們真的認為那樣做能幫助他?
And you really think that this is gonna help him?
他失去了他的孩子
He lost his child.
而現在他不介意失去所有
And now he doesn't care if he loses everything else.
我們不能讓這發生
We just can't let that happen.
我們要帶他回來現實
We have to bring him back.
$20,000物有所值
$20,000's worth it.
- 我會付的   - Claire!
- I'll pay for it.   - Claire!
我會自己交出錢來, 我不在意
I'll pay for it. I'll pay for it myself. I don't care.
那規則呢?
So, what are the rules?
首先我們需要簽合同
Well, first, we'd have to sign a confidentiality agreement.
確保你們不說出去, 因為...
And make sure that you don't talk about it, 'cause...
我不是指法律條款
No, I don't mean the legal rules.
我指這齣戲
I mean, the rules of the theatrical device.
例如, 其他人也能看到我們嗎? 還是只有Howard?
I mean, do other people see us, or only Howard?
- 對, 其他人也能看到他們嗎, Whit?   -Whit?
- Yeah, do other people see them, Whit?  - Whit?
我猜...只有Howard吧
I guess... I guess only Howard.
那就是我們想要的效果吧?
That's the effect we're looking for, right?
- 猜?   - 你猜? 我...
- Guess?   - You guess? I mean...
抱歉, 你到底有沒有想清楚?
I'm sorry, have you thought this through?
- 當然有   - 沒有
- Sure. Sure.   - No.
- 一定程度吧   - 不, 我們沒有
- I mean, to a degree.   - No, we haven't.
沒有, Whit, 停下, 我們沒有想清楚
No, we haven't, Whit. Shut up! Like... We haven't.
假設他們想要到酒吧裡喝一杯呢?
For instance, what if they go into a bar and they want to order a drink?
他們如何能...
How can they do that if...
你近來有看見Howard進酒吧嗎?
Do you see Howard walking into a lot of bars these days?
隨便吧, 那不重要
Whatever. Doesn't matter.
- 那Howard突然想去俱樂部呢?   - 他們是演員
- I mean, what if Howard goes clubbing?  - They're actors.
- 他們需要預備這種情況    - 夠了夠了
- They need to know hypothetically.
- Okay. Okay. Enough. Enough.
我們有選擇被誰看見, 何時看見的能力
We have the power to be seen by whomever we want, whenever we want.
- 那怎樣?    - 不錯, 我喜歡
- How's that?   - I like that, I like that.
- 我說過他們是好演員  - 我喜歡
- I told you they were good.   - I like that, yeah.
我們該留給他們想
We should just leave it to them.
繼續
Let's move on.
下一步呢?
What's next?
Howard寫了三封信, 分別給愛情, 時間和死亡
Howard wrote three letters to Love, Death and Time.
所以我想唯一的問題是, 誰扮演哪個?
So, I guess the only question is who plays who?
選角, 非常重要
Casting. Very important.
愛情
Love.
死亡
Death.
時間
Time.
很好, 我們何時收到報酬?
Great. When do we get paid?
致死亡, 你經過很多神話
"Dear Death, you travel with so much mythology,
給予很多傷痛, 引起很多恐懼
"cause so much pain, inspire such fear.
但你對我來說紙老虎
"But you're a paper tiger to me.
你只是個可悲又沒作為的中層管理人員
"You're just pathetic and powerless middle management.
你甚至沒有權力去做一個簡單的交易
"You don't even have the authority to make a simple trade."
你也看到, 這不是位支持者寫的信
As you can see, it's not exactly a fan letter.
對, 死亡沒有很多支持者
Yeah, well, Death doesn't have any fans.
我不明白你們為何這樣做, 因為這也算是解放
I don't understand why, because it's a liberation.
你還好嗎?
Hey, you okay?
他上班, 然後去寵物公園
He goes to work, and the dog park.
就這兩個地方
And that's it.
好吧, 這就是我會做的
Okay. So, here's how I'm gonna do it.
我會很憤怒的走上他面前
I'm gonna come to him angry.
非常憤怒的, 像我們有問題要解決
Like, pissed off. Like, we got a problem.
不, 別這樣做
No, no, no. Don't do that.
他說我是木和壞死組織, 他在呼喚我
He's calling me wood and dead tissue. He's calling me out.
這怎算呼喚你?
How's he calling you out?
是時間
Time.
[找尋一個更安全的捐贈者]
他在呼喚時間, 而我就是時間
He's calling out Time, and I'm Time.
我不想你去跟Howard對抗
Look, I don't want you antagonizing Howard.
你明白嗎?
Do you get that?
但信裡只寫了"再見"
But the letter only consists of one word, "Goodbye."
看
Look.
致愛情, 再見
"Dear Love, goodbye."
我到底要跟他說甚麼?
What am I even supposed to say to him?
那...
Um, it's...
這是封道別愛情的信, 對吧?
It's a letter to Love saying goodbye, right?
- 對   - 那假如你走上前
- Yeah.    - So, what if you approach him,
然後說你拒絕接受?
and you refuse to accept that?
你說他不能那麼容易就擺脫你
You say he can't get rid of you that easily.
告訴他
Tell him that
我們沒有選擇愛誰和被誰受的權利
we don't get to choose who we love and who loves us back.
告訴他你在他之中
Tell him that you're within him,
你在萬物之中, 無論他喜歡與否
you're within everything, whether he likes it or not.
如果他接受了
And if he accepts that,
那可能... 我不知道
then maybe... I don't know.
他可能找回他的生存意義
Maybe he gets to find his life again.
他們會悲傷
They grieve.
狗隻們
Dogs.
他們會悲傷, 而且了解死亡
They grieve, and they fully understand death.
你說我是紙老虎
You called me a paper tiger.
在你給我的信當中
In the letter you wrote me.
你說我可悲
You said I was pathetic.
嗯
Mmm.
你不記得了嗎?
You don't remember?
你說了一堆中層管理人員
You went on about middle management,
做交易, 紙老虎
making a deal, paper tiger.
Howard, 那才過不久
Oh, Howard, it wasn't that long ago.
你從哪拿到的?
Where did you get that?
- 你是誰?   - 你寫給誰?
- Who are you?   - Who did you write the letter to?
我寫給死亡
I wrote the letter to Death.
很高興認識你, 我肯定你被迷倒了
Nice to meet you. Charmed, I'm sure.
不
No.
我明白
I know, I know.
人們經常寫信給宇宙
People write letters to the universe all the time.
大部份都沒有得到答覆
Most don't get a personal response.
但你有, 因為我只想告訴你, 你錯了
But you are, because I just wanted to tell you that you're wrong.
我不是甚麼沒作為的中層管理人員
I'm not some powerless middle management
- 還有只跟從指令   - 小姐
- just following orders.   - Miss...
我不想做交易, 是我決定的
You see, I didn't want to make the trade. It was my call.
我不想聽你說
I don't want this. I don't want this.
我沒有對你的工作指指點點
Now, I don't tell you how to do your job.
所以我也希望你別教我如何工作
So, I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell me how to do mine.
那個男人在跟誰說話? 他看起來有點怪
Who's that man talking to? He looks kind of weird.
別擔心, 有時候人們做些不能理解的事
Don't worry about that. Sometimes people are silly.
你看, 他們看不到我存在, 直到輪到他們
You see, they don't see me till it's their time.
沒事的, Howard, 還沒輪到你
Oh, it's okay, Howard. It's not your time yet.
我只想交還你這個
I just wanted to return this
並且解決我們之間的恩怨
and clear things up between us.
我真的是死亡, Howard
I really am Death, Howard!
他信了
He believed me.
我告訴你, 他信了
I'm telling you he believed me.
- 真棒   - 那非常精彩
- That's amazing.   - I mean, that was spectacular.
因為沒有第二次機會
Because there was no safety net, you see.
那真的太Grotowski了 [一名導演]
That... That... That was Grotowski.
- 那簡直是Stella Adler [演員]   - 對
- That was pure Stella Adler!   - Ah!
- 謝謝你給予我這個機會   - 對
- Thank you. Thank you for the opportunity.   - Yes.
- 你真是個好人   - 不成問題
- You are a kind man.   - Oh, not a problem.
- 他信了, 我告訴你   - 我不會這麼肯定
- He believed me, I'm telling you.   - I wouldn't go that far.
他需要這個, 我可以從他的眼睛裡看到
But he needed it. I could tell. I could tell in his eyes.
那個女人和小男孩是誰? 時機很棒
Who was that woman and that little boy? That was incredible.
那是我們的私家偵探和她的孫子
Oh, that was our private investigator and her grandson.
真的? 她有說我的演出怎樣嗎?
Oh, really? And did she say anything about me?
她說你很好
She said you were good. She said really good.
好? 甚麼意思? 像...
"Good"? What do you mean? Good like...
像捲心菜一樣好還是甚麼?
You mean good like cabbage is good, or what?
不不, 她...出色
No, no. She... Great.
她說:她將不可能化為可能
She said, she said, "She made the impossible possible."
我該給你錢
I should be paying you.
他們當時告訴我Trevor已收拾好他的包袱
They told me that Trevor had packed his little suitcase,
他說他要回家了
that he said he was going home.
我憤怒極了
I was furious.
但他在睡, 所以我沒有跟他說話
But he was sleeping, so I couldn't talk to him.
甚麼樣的護士會答應一個正在慢慢死去的五歲小男孩
I mean, what nurse promises this dying five-year-old little boy
他能回家?
he could go home?
他幾乎沒剩多少白血球
He barely had any white blood cells left.
他很脆弱
He was so fragile.
誰能這麼殘忍呢?
And who could be so cruel?
誰能對他撒謊呢?
Who could do that?
所以當然, 我失控了
So, of course I'm frantic.
我對職員大聲責罵, 只想尋根究底
I am shouting at the staff, trying to get to the bottom of it.
Trevor終於醒了
Well, Trevor finally wakes up
我走上前
and I go to him.
他的藍色包包還放在床尾
You know, his little blue suitcase was still at the edge of the bed, right.
我看著他並問
So, I look at him and ask,
誰跟你說的, 寶目?
"Who said that to you, sweetie?
誰說你可以回到我們的房子?
"Who said that you could come back to our house?"
你知道他怎樣回答嗎?
You know what he says?
沒有人, 媽媽
"Nobody, Mommy.
我不是回我們的房子
"I'm not going back to our house.
我是回我所屬之處
"I'm going home."
他四小時後過世了
He died four hours later.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
你在找"小翅膀支援團隊"嗎?
Are you looking for Smallest Wings Support Group?
嗯...
Um...
- 對   - 你是?
- Yes.   - And you are?
- Howard   - Howard
- Um, Howard.   - Howard.
進去坐下吧
Come on in. Have a seat.
你失去了孩子嗎, Howard?
Did you lose a child, Howard?
對
Yeah.
- 男還是女?   - 啊...
- Boy or girl?   - Uh...
女兒
A girl.
那她的名字是?
And what was her name?
沒關係, Howard
No, it's okay. Howard.
你不必回答
You don't have to answer.
你甚至不需要說話
You don't even have to talk, okay?
可以留下嗎?
You stick around?
拜託?
Please?
好了
Okay.
謝謝你的分享
Thank you so much for sharing.
我們都很感謝
We really appreciate it.
謝謝
Thank you.
有人想要分享甚麼嗎?
Does anybody have anything else they'd like to say?
- 你今晚為何打算進來?   - 嗯?
- So, why'd you decide to come in tonight?  - Hmm?
我以前看過你站在外面
Yeah, I've... I've seen you outside.
我早晚打算邀請你進來
I was gonna come out one night and invite you in,
但我猜我不想暴露你的隱藏位置
but I guess I didn't want to blow up your spot.
暴露我的隱藏位置?
Blow up my spot?
- 對   - 你不想打亂我的節奏?
- Yeah.   - You didn't want to mess up my jam?
正是
Exactly.
你叫甚麼?
What's your name?
我是Madeline
I'm Madeline.
很高興認識你
Nice to meet you.
我女兒叫Olivia
My daughter's name was Olivia.
她因為一種叫膠質母細胞瘤的罕有腦癌而過世
She died of a rare form of brain cancer
known as Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或簡稱GBM
or GBM for short.
她當時六歲
She was six years old.
你的女兒叫甚麼, Howard?
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
好吧
Okay.
不要緊, 別回答, 我不想折磨你
Fine. Don't answer. I'm not gonna torture you.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 是因為節日嗎?   - 嗯?
- Was it the holidays?   - Mmm?
你今晚進來的原因
Why you decided to come in tonight.
有很多第一次來的人都是在節日期間
We get a lot of first-timers during the holidays.
- 不, 不是因為這個  - 那為甚麼是今晚?
- No, that's not it.   - Then why tonight?
我想...
Uh, I guess...
我...
I'm, uh...
我在試著解開心結
I'm trying to fix my mind.
你失去了孩子, Howard
You lost a child, Howard.
你的心結永遠都會在
It'll never be fixed.
我希望你會再來
I hope you come back.
嗨
Hey.
這是簽妥了的合約和保密協議
Signed contracts and confidentiality agreements.
- 太好了, 謝謝   - 所以他有說甚麼嗎?
- Oh, great. Thank you. - So, did he say something?
誰啊? Howard?
Who, Howard?
- 不幸的, 沒有   - 他信了
- No. Unfortunately, he didn't. - He believed it, I'm telling you.
- 那真是太好了  - 或許你該再派我去了
- Oh, that's good. - Maybe you should send me in again.
而不是Raffi, 他太急躁了
Not Raffi. Raffi's too impetuous.
還有Amy, 她太感情用事
And Amy, she's just so emotional.
除了我, 還有誰?
After me, what is there?
他共寫了三封信
Well, he did write three letters.
但死亡比時間重要多了
But Death is so much more vital than Time.
- 對   - 死亡給予時間意義
- Right.   - Death gives Time all of its value.
或許全都該由我扮演
Maybe... Maybe I should play all the parts.
你知道現時人口統計中的新任父母的數字比以往高吧?
You know the highest margin demographic is new parents now?
他們製造出一條算法
Target actually invented an algorithm
去推算他們的女性客戶何時會懷孕
to predict when their female customers were gonna get pregnant.
你之前說過你不適
You said before that you weren't okay.
你患病了嗎?
Are you sick?
對
I'm sick.
你可以說我的病情非常嚴重
You could say, uh, I'm very sick.
你要死了嗎?
You're dying?
每個人都在死去
Everyone's dying.
對, 但你時日無多
Yeah, but you're doing it now.
Simon. Simon.
來吧, 告訴我, 是甚麼病? 有甚麼不對勁了?
Come on, tell me. Tell me. What is it? What's wrong?
有甚麼不對勁?
What's wrong?
就是我病情惡化了
What's wrong is that I came out of remission
在我兒子出生前的兩週
two weeks before my son was born.
是我
What's wrong
每天都要裝作我還很健康
is that I'm running a marathon every day pretending to be healthy.
那就是不對勁的地方
That's what's wrong.
你有跟誰說過嗎?
Have you told anyone?
沒有?
You haven't?
沒有, 就一個我幾乎不認識卻又不斷質問我的女演員
No, just some pushy actress that I don't really know.
甚麼病?
What is it?
是多發性骨髓瘤
It's multiple myeloma.
我16歲時發病, 25歲又重發
I fought it when I was 16, and then again when I was 25.
它從沒離開過
It just never went away.
反而組織起來變得更強
Instead it regrouped and got stronger.
所以沒法醫治?
So, the war's over?
對
Yeah, war's over.
你的身後事處理好了嗎?
Are your affairs in order?
沒有
My affairs are not in order.
所以我聘請了你
That's why I hired you.
我要離開我的家人已經夠壞了
It's bad enough that I'm leaving my family.
我不會讓他們之後身無分文
I'm not gonna leave them penniless.
他信了我
He believed me.
Howard.
他信了我
He believed me.
抱歉, 別碰
Hey. Excuse me. No, don't touch that.
我不明白骨牌
I don't understand dominoes.
沒有計分牌, 或者一個籃框
There's no board to play them on, or basket to throw them into.
對
Right. Um...
我想你去錯地方了
I think you might be in the wrong place.
不, 我沒去錯, Howard
No, I'm in the right place, Howard.
對吧
Mmm. Yeah.
致時間, 人們說你是一切傷害的良藥
"Time, they say you heal all wounds,
但他們不會說起你如何將一切美好化為腐朽
"but they don't talk about how you destroy
all that's good in the world.
如何將美麗的事物化作塵埃
"How you turn beauty into ash."
那真是一派胡言, Howard
Now that's some bullshit, Howard.
如果愛情是創造而死亡是破壞
If Love is creation and Death is destruction,
我就只是他們兩者之間
I'm just a terrain in between.
你不了解時間, 沒有人了解時間
You don't understand Time. No one understands Time.
愛因斯坦幾乎弄清, 他說我是幻想
I mean, Einstein came close when he said I was an illusion.
Howard? 嘿
Howard? Hey. Uh...
聽著, 我很肯定你會回答"不"
Listen, I'm sure it's a "no"
但Oneida Apparel服裝公司要求你在會議出現
but Oneida Apparel asked that you be in the media buy meeting.
很抱歉我阻礙了你
I'm sorry to just barge in.
問她
Ask her.
問她能不能看到我
Go ahead. Ask her if she can see me.
我不會在會議出現
I'm not gonna be in the meeting.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
他們堅持要我問你
Well, they insisted I ask.
他們很可能會跟我們解約, 所以...
I mean, they're probably gonna fire us, so...
好吧
Okay.
- 太好了   - 我去
- Awesome.   - Yes.
好吧
Okay.
晚點見
See you later.
你可以拿回這個, Howard
You can have this back, Howard.
你到底為何寫信給我?
Why did you write me anyway?
是因為你需要我
You wrote me because you need me.
不
No. Um...
我不需要你, 明白嗎?
I don't need anything from you, okay?
你們都喜歡埋怨
You all like to bitch and complain.
不夠時間
"There isn't enough time."
人生苦短
"Life is short."
看, 白髮都出來了
"Oh, here, the gray hairs are coming in."
一天其實長得很
You know, a day is long as hell.
我非常充沛, 我是份禮物
I'm abundant. I'm a gift.
即使現在你站在這裡抱怨
Even while you're standing here talking shit,
也是份禮物, 而你浪費了
I'm gifting you, and you're wasting it.
用在甚麼上了?
On what?
這是甚麼?
I mean, what is this? Huh?
嘿!
Hey, hey!
你知道嗎You know,
我才應該寫信埋怨
I should be the one that's writing angry letters.
那是我做過最差勁的一件事
That was the worst thing I've ever done.
那是我做過最好的一件事
That was the best thing I've ever done.
你剛才說甚麼愛因斯坦?
What was that thing you said about Einstein in there?
愛因斯坦說時間是固執又堅持的幻像
Einstein called time a stubbornly persistent illusion.
那究竟是甚麼?
What's that even mean?
時間不是從一月走到十二月
Time doesn't go from January to December,
或從早到晚
or from noon to midnight.
那只是人類的觀點
You know, we all just make it that way in our heads.
荒謬至極
That's absurd.
你試著跟一個在婚禮上遲到的人說這個
Try telling that to a person who's an hour late to a wedding
或是跟一個剛被判20年監牢的人說
or was just sentenced to 20 years in jail.
或是一個快更年期的女人
Or someone fighting a baby clock.
我們其實不需要交心
We really don't need to have this conversation, ever.
無論如何
Anyway, just...
你今天做得很好
Yeah, wanted to say great job today.
只是個固執的幻像, Claire
Just a stubborn illusion, Claire.
你還有很多時間
You have all the time in the world.
你是九點
You're nine!
"You're nine."
你好
Hi.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你一定在開玩笑吧
You gotta be friggin' kidding me.
我在用餐
I'm eating.
你說了再見, 而那...
You said goodbye, and that...
我們沒有選擇愛誰和被誰愛的權利
We don't get to choose who we love or who loves us back.
那代表你只要還在世就無法對我做甚麼
And that means you're powerless to me as long as you're alive
因為我是生命的基本
because I'm the fabric of life.
我在你當中, 我在萬物當中
I'm within you. I'm within everything.
Howard,
如果你能接受, 那可能...
if you can accept that, then maybe...
我不知道, 但你可能可以重新過活
I don't know, but maybe you get to live again.
我失敗了
I completely screwed it up.
我太悲哀和充滿了歉意
I was weepy and apologetic.
我認為愛也可以是那樣
Well, I think love can be weepy and apologetic.
我想我最後還算可以
I think I was better at the end.
嘿, 我肯定你盡力了
Hey, hey. I'm sure you were great.
你真好
You're sweet.
我可以吻你嗎?
Can I kiss you?
你不需要將它性化
You don't have to sexualize it.
我可以不性化地吻你
I can kiss you without sexualizing it.
真的, 我試過沒有性愛的性
Seriously, I've had sex without sexualizing it.
你應該停在"好"的階段, Whit
You should take "sweet", Whit.
算是升職了
It's a promotion.
無法抗拒才算是升職
"Irresistible" would be a promotion.
他信了
He believes it.
你怎知道?
How could you tell?
我從他的眼中看到
I could tell by his eyes.
很好, 但除了你沒人看到
That's great, but no one else has seen it
而那終究是我們的目的
and that's ultimately what we need to have happen.
我們認為你們該再接觸他
We think if you would engage with him
- 在公眾場合   - 很好了
- one more time, um, in public.   - Great.
但這次試著...
But this time try to...
但你們需要挑釁讓他有很大的舉動
But you need to provoke a strong visible reaction.
為甚麼?
Why?
因為我們的私家偵探會錄影
Because our private investigator's gonna capture it on video.
並用來做證據
And we're gonna use it as evidence.
那就好像拍電影
It'll be like being in a movie.
除了會後期加工將你們除去
Except you'll be digitally removed.
不要
No.
甚麼?
Sorry?
太激烈了
This is too intense.
抱歉, 我不能繼續
Um, I'm sorry. I can't be a part of this.
Amy, 演戲裡沒有甚麼叫"激烈"
Amy, there is no "too intense" in acting.
你想被愛還是被記住?
Do you wanna be loved or do you wanna make an impact?
這不是Noël Coward [演員]
I mean, this isn't Noël Coward.
這是...Chekhov [短篇小說家]
This is... This is Chekhov.
這是荒謬!
This is horrible!
你知道的
The... You know,
你曾經跟他一起創辦那間機構吧, Whit?
you did start the agency with him, didn't you, Whit?
Claire, 他是你的導師
And, Claire, he was your mentor.
Simon, 他讓你成為持有人
And, Simon, he gave you part ownership in a business
而他完全沒有必要
when he absolutely didn't have to.
我跟她說過了點我們的事
I may have told her a few things...
我們...
when we were...
抱歉, 這不能接受
I'm sorry, this is horrible.
我不能...參與其中, 謝謝
I... I can't...No, I can't be a part of this. Thank you.
- 抱歉, 謝謝了   - Amy, 別走
- Sorry. Thanks.   - Amy, no.
Amy.
Amy, 別走
Amy. No.
她太多心了
Oh, she's so passionate, you know.
Amy!
抱歉, 她會回來的
I'm so sorry. She will be back.
但如果她不回來
But if she isn't, um,
我會介入, 我很熟悉愛情
I'll step in. I do know all about love.
Amy!
我錯過了甚麼?
What'd I miss?
人們都在為他們死去的孩子們哭
People crying because their kids died.
有種病叫喪失性幻覺
Uh, there's a thing called bereavement hallucinations.
對
Yes.
Right. Um. Okay.
所以...
So, uh...
我查了一下
I looked them up.
有點東西我明白, 我不睡覺的
And here's the thing. I don't sleep.
是的
Okay.
不太睡覺
Like, not a lot.
我會睡
I mean, I sleep.
但可能一星期只睡六, 七小時
But I get six or seven hours a week.
現在我回想起來, 那可能就是為甚麼...
Now that I think about it, that's probably why...
甚麼為甚麼?
Why what?
我在談話
I'm having conversations.
我指, 談話
I mean, conversations.
對
Okay.
沒關係了
It's okay. Never mind. Um...
- Howard?   - 是
- Howard?   - Yeah.
你想跟我談話嗎?
You wanna have a conversation with me?
是
Uh, yes.
所以我可以假設你是那79%之一?
So, I assume you're a part of the 79%?
嗯?
Mmm?
79%夫婦喪子後會離婚
Of couples who get divorced after losing a child.
對
Yeah.
對, 我也是
Yeah, me too.
你還愛她嗎?
Do you still love her?
我甚至已經不知道甚麼是愛
I don't even know what love is anymore.
你還愛他嗎?
Do you still love him?
我們從沒停止愛過對方
We never fell out of love.
至少, 我不認為, 只是...
At least, I don't think so. It's just...
我們可以...
We can...
我們辦妥了離婚手續的那天, 他給了我這個
The day our divorce was final, he sent me this.
如果我們可以重新相遇一次就好了
"If only we could be strangers again."
現在我們是
Now we are.
這是他做過最浪漫的舉動
The most romantic gesture he ever made.
所以, 回答你剛才的問題
So, to answer your question,
對
yes,
我還愛著他
I still love him.
你甚麼意思
What did you mean
當你說你在談話?
when you said you were having conversations?
對
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
跟誰談話?
Conversations with who?
不是誰
It's not "who."
那真是...
It's really... It's...
你會以為我瘋了
You're gonna think I'm crazy.
說一下
Try me.
我可以帶你去看嗎?
Um, can I show you?
不會分解的壞死組織
"Dead tissue that won't decompose."
他那時就坐在這裡
He was sitting right here.
就是個說話刻薄又驕傲的小流氓
Just a mean, little, arrogant thug.
他是第一個出現的吧?
And he was the first one that appeared, right?
不, 死亡先出現
Uh, no. Death came first.
她在寵物公園找到我
She met me in the dog park.
所以死亡是個女人?
Oh, so Death is a "her"?
對, 原來死亡是個白種婆婆
Uh, yeah. It turns out Death is an elderly white woman.
甚麼交易?
What was the trade?
你說死亡不跟你做交易
You said Death wouldn't make the trade.
甚麼意思?
What does that mean?
當我們意識到...
When we realized our...
我的女兒在死去, 我祈禱
My daughter was dying, I prayed, uh...
不是向上帝或者宇宙, 而是向死亡
Not to God or the universe, but to Death.
我提出一個交易
I offered a trade.
帶走我
Take me,
留下我的女兒
leave my daughter.
但死亡不想交易, 所以...
But she didn't wanna make the trade, so...
所以誰贏了那回合?
So, who won that round?
你還是瓷器?
You or the porcelain?
瓷器, 它從未輸過
Porcelain. Porcelain's undefeated.
抱歉, 我以為所有人都走了
I'm sorry about that, I thought everyone left.
對, 他們走了, 但我還沒
Yes, they did. But I'm here to close up.
很好
Good.
你需要我幫手帶你回家嗎?
You need help getting home?
不, 我沒事
No. I'm fine.
我很好
I'm... I'm good.
我搜尋了你
I Googled you.
- 你搜尋了?   - 對
- You did?   - Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God.
從一無所有
You came from nothing.
捱過杜克大學
You put yourself through Duke,
娶了個美麗的女人
you married a wonderful woman,
是個很有愛心的父親
you're a loving father.
你活得不錯, 你活過了
So, you lived well. You lived right.
但朋友, 你現在這樣是不對的
But, my friend, you're not dying right.
你打算告訴我如何死嗎?
Are you gonna tell me how to die?
你跟你的家人說過了嗎?
Have you told your family yet?
- 沒   - 你這不是在幫他們
- Mmm-mmm.   - You're not helping them.
你只是在否定他們得知真相的權利
You're just denying them what is rightfully theirs.
是嗎? 甚麼真相?
Yeah? And what's that?
痛苦? 萎縮? 疾病?
Pain? Atrophy? Disease?
對, 正是
Yes. Yes.
全部都是
All of it.
還有告別的機會
And the chance to say goodbye.
還是專注演出吧
Stick to acting.
好了
Okay.
我有件我從沒跟別人說過的事
I have something that I haven't told anyone.
不關於信或天使或者甚麼
It doesn't involve letters or angels or anything like that,
但它對我意義重大
but it means something to me.
他們當時在準備告別Olivia
They were preparing Olivia to say goodbye.
我的丈夫在停車場嘗試讓我母親冷靜下來
And my husband was trying to calm my mother in the parking lot
因為她完全不能接受
because she lost it.
所以我當時獨自一人
So I was alone
坐在
and I was sitting there
布碌崙瑪摩利醫院的等候室
in the waiting room at Maimonides Hospital.
那裡有個女人坐在我旁邊
And there was this woman who sat next to me.
她問我我要失去誰了
And she asked me who I was about to lose.
我告訴了她
And I told her.
然後她看著我並說
And she looked at me and she said,
記著留意
"Just be sure to notice
附屬的美麗
"the collateral beauty."
她...
I mean, she...
她說得很隨口
She said it so casually.
一牆之隔
In the next room,
我的六歲女兒正在被拆下維持生命的機器
my six-year-old daughter was being taken off life support.
而那女人說附屬的美麗
And this woman says "collateral beauty."
人們都不知道那種時候該說甚麼
People don't know what to say in those moments.
不, 她知道
No, she did.
只是當時我沒有意會到
I just didn't get it at the time.
那不是因為同情我或者氣氛尷尬
See, it wasn't said out of sympathy or awkwardness.
那是經驗之談
It was from experience.
約一年後
About a year later,
有些事開始發生在我身上了
something started to happen to me, you know.
我會在街上或地下鐵走著
I would be walking or on the subway, whatever,
然後突然大哭起來
and I would just burst into tears.
但那不是為Olivia留下的淚
But these weren't Olivia tears.
那是因為有東西重生了而留
These were tears born from something else,
因為對一切深刻的連繫而留
from this kind of profound connection to everything.
然後我意識到了
And I realized
那就是附屬的美麗
it was the collateral beauty.
那真是...
I mean, there's...
世上沒有一種叫附屬的美麗
There's no such thing as collateral beauty.
有的, Howard
There is, Howard.
真的有
There really is.
雖然那不會讓她活過來
It'll never bring her back.
也不會讓我忘掉一切
And it will never ever make it okay.
但我保證你, 它真的存在
But I promise you, it's there.
好吧
Okay.
你需要跟他們說話, Howard
You need to talk to them, Howard.
聽著
Look, um...
很感謝你分享的故事
Appreciate your story,
但我沒有感覺到這附屬美麗
but I'm not really feeling the "collateral beauty" thing.
我不在乎
I don't care!
對他們呼喊, 跟他們說道理, 挑戰他們
Yell at them, reason with them, challenge them.
就試著接觸他們
Just engage!
我想這一切都是錯誤的
I think this was a mistake.
- 你好   - 你好
- Hi.   - Hi.
你在這裡做甚麼?
What're you doing here?
Brigitte告訴我在這裡可以找到你
Uh, Brigitte told me this is where I could find you.
當然吧
Of course she did.
我們可以走走, 聊聊天?
Could we just go and talk somewhere for 15 minutes by ourselves?
我其實在工作, 我在排練
I'm... I'm actually working. I'm rehearsing right now.
- 你在這裡也排練?   - 對
- You're rehearsing here, too?  - Yeah.
你同時間在做多少工作?
How many projects are you doing at the same time?
現時的話三件
I'm currently doing three.
三件, 嘩
Three. Wow.
- 對   - 一定很忙
- Yeah.   - That's really busy.
那我們哪有時間去吃晚餐?
How are we gonna fit a dinner date in?
Whit...
聽著, 真的
Listen, listen, listen. Seriously...
我想讓你重新考慮你昨晚所說的
I have to ask you to reconsider what you said last night.
我們需要你再一次的幫忙
We need you one more time.
就一場戲
Just give us one more scene.
我不會去的
I am out.
Amy, 你想要...
Amy, what do you...
等下, 我可以說甚麼? 你想要...
Wait, what can I say? What do you...
事成我會給你$100,000, 不是20,000
I'll give you $100,000. Not 20, 100.
你沒有$100,000
You don't have $100,000.
對, 我跟我母親一起住
You're right. I live with my mother.
但這會成事的, 而完成後, 我會有很多錢
But this is gonna work, and when it does, I'll have much, much more.
我會給你一百萬
And I'll give you a million.
- 我不想要你的錢   - 我真的會
- I don't want your money.   - I really will.
我不想要你的錢
I do not want your money.
你知道嗎, 我從不想要你的錢
Do you know, I've actually never wanted your money.
我到底要說甚麼才能讓你回來?
What can I say to get you to do this?
因為有太多緊急的事要處理, 你甚至不會想到
Because there's so much more at stake here, you have no idea.
噢
Oh.
你有個女兒吧?
You have a daughter, right?
對
Yeah.
我有說過嗎?
Did we talk about that?
告訴我她出生的那天你的感受
Tell me what it was like the day that she was born.
甚麼?
What?
對你而言那是甚麼感受?
What it felt like for you.
很可怕
Uh, it was scary.
非常可怕, 我完全不知所措
It was very scary. I was terrified.
但當他們讓我抱著她
But then they gave her to me
我感覺到了前所未有的感覺
and I had the most amazing sensation run through me.
那...我不能說...
It... I can't...
甚麼? 說完它
What? Finish it.
那聽起來很愚蠢
It sounds... It's goofy.
不, 那聽起來不愚蠢
No, it doesn't sound goofy.
這其實是我第一次感覺到
Do you know, actually, this is the first time that I felt
我對你的事有興趣
any attraction towards you, whatsoever.
- 真的嗎?   - 是
- Really?   - Yes.
我看著她, 然後我...
I looked at her and I...
我意識到我沒有感受到愛意
I realized that I wasn't feeling love.
我成為了愛
I had become love.
雖然她現在不再跟我說話
She doesn't talk to me now, though.
她把離婚責怪於我, 她還在生我氣
She blames me for the divorce, and so she's angry at me.
而...
And...
這是我值得的下場
I deserve it.
我跟你做個交易
I'm gonna make you a deal.
如果你能將這些
If you can take all of this,
坦白又積極的決心
frankly, aggressive determination
還有非凡的開放態度
and extraordinary openness
用在贏回你女兒的心上
and use it on winning your daughter back,
那我就幫你們
then I'll do it.
約定了
It's a deal.
你沒感受到嗎?
See, you don't feel that?
放開我
Oh, wow. Give me my hand back.
你感受到的吧?
You feel that though, right? You feel it?
- 那就是火花   - 再見, Whit
- That's sparks.   - Goodbye, Whit.
那就是火花
That's what that is.
[律師信]
[關於宏盟集團, 盡快聯絡]
嗨, 怎樣了?
Hey! What's up?
- 甚麼?   - 你有點話要說嗎?
- What?   - You got something to say?
你有點想要說的話吧?
You got something you wanna say?
對, 我有很多事想告訴你
Oh, yeah. I got a lot of things I'd like to say to you.
說出來啊!
Well, say it. Say it!
你就只會浪費時間
See, you just waste time.
我給予了你這份禮物, 而你就白白浪費它
See, I give you a gift and you just waste it!
我不在乎時間
I don't care about time.
這是監禁
This is a prison sentence!
我不想要你的所謂禮物
I don't want your gift!
因為你拿走了她的時間
Because you took hers.
噢, 又來了
Oh, come on.
你是來帶我走的嗎?
Are you here to take me?
不, Howard, 我來這裡跟你一起坐車
No, Howard. I'm here to ride the F train with you.
好吧
Oh, okay.
我說, 有對龍鳳胎在肚裡
So, there are these two twins in a womb, a boy and a girl.
你在說笑話嗎?
You telling a joke?
不, 這是個故事
No, no. It's a story.
這對雙胞胎非常快樂
So, these twins are happy.
有食物, 又溫暖, 他們感到很安全
They're fed, they're warm, they feel safe.
但他們越來越大, 不夠位置
But they're outgrowing their space
他們意識到這不是辦法
and they realize this can't go on forever.
所以他們開始想
So they start thinking,
接下來會怎樣?
"What comes next?
如果變得又冷又寂寞呢?
"What if it's cold or lonely?
如果我們不再在一起呢?
"What if we're not together?
如果這根本甚麼都不是呢?
"What if there's nothing at all?"
然後那女孩看著臍帶
So, then the girl looks at the cord.
那條一直給他們養分的臍帶
This cord that has fed them, has nourished them,
那條他們根本不可能猜透的臍帶
this cord that they can't possibly conceive
很可能連繫在任何東西上
could be attached to anything else.
然後她說
And she says,
我們沒有證據
"Well, we have no proof.
我們只有這個
"All we have is this."
不
No.
那真是深奧
Wow, that's deep.
所以就是生命吧
So, it's like life after birth.
充滿希望
Hopeful.
你到底想要甚麼?
All right, what do you want?
你為何來這裡?
Why are you here?
你的陳詞濫調我都聽膩了
I've heard all of your platitudes.
我都明白了
I got them, I know.
她去了更好的地方
"She's in a better place."
冥冥中自有主宰
And, "This is all a part of a master plan."
也聽過了
Heard that one, too.
接下來是我最喜歡的
Here's my favorite.
上帝從天上看下來, 看見了一朵最美麗的玫瑰花
"God looked down and saw the most beautiful rose,
太美麗了, 所以他摘下來
"so beautiful that he picked it
放在天堂裡陪伴他
"to have it in Heaven all for Himself."
然後就是關於科學, 生物中心主義
Then there's the science, biocentrism,
我們在無數宇宙中誕生和死去
and we're all living and dying in infinite universes
同時間
all at the same time.
還有宗教
And then the religion,
基督教和救贖
the Christians and their salvation,
佛教及其輪迴之說, 還有印度教及其聖禮
and the Buddhists and their Samsara,
and the Hindus and their 41 st sacrament.
特別忘不了那些詩句
And can't forget the poetry.
噢, 那些詩句
Oh, the poetry.
死並不像一般人所想像的
"To die is different from what anyone supposed
而是更幸運
"and luckier."
Whitman. [Walt Whitman - Song of Myself]
怒斥吧
And, "Rage...
怒斥光的消逝
"Rage against the dying of the light.
年邁的智者深知黑暗必將來臨
"Though wise men at their end know dark is right."
[Dylan Thomas - Do Not Go Gentle into that Good Night]
Thomas. And then...
划呀划, 划小船, 緩緩順流下
Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream
開心呀, 開心呀, 開心呀, 開心吧
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily
人生不過一場夢
Life is but a dream
我知道了
I got it.
我全都明白了!
I got it!
全都在說你是生命的必經的階段
It all basically says that you're a natural part of life,
我們不該恨你和害怕你
we shouldn't hate you, we shouldn't fear you.
我猜我們該坦然接受你對吧?
I guess we should just accept you, right?
就這樣?
That's it?
我明白了, 不過我想說
I get it. Here's the thing.
這全都是讀書人的一派胡言而已
It's all a bunch of intellectual bullshit
因為她此時此地不在
because she's not here holding my fucking hand.
你好, Howard
Hi, Howard.
你又要哭了嗎?
You gonna cry again?
你不喜歡我傷心時的模樣?
You don't like it when I'm sad?
- 你不是整天都傷心的嗎?   - 當然不是
- Ah, aren't you always sad?   - No.
我可以有其他心情, 我可以是快樂
No, I can be other things. I can be happy.
我可以是意想不到和不可預測的
I can be unexpected and unpredictable...
還有性感, 溫馨, 神秘...
...and sexy and warm and mysterious and...
和窩心
And home.
我可以很窩心, Howard, 你記得嗎?
I can be home, Howard, you remember?
你記得我嗎?
Do you remember me?
聽著, 那些甚麼"生命的基本", 留給跟別人說吧
Listen. All the "fabric of life" bullshit,
save that for somebody else.
那不是胡說的
It's not bullshit.
我知道你不相信我, 但你要給我另一次機會
I know you don't believe me,
but you have to trust me.
相信你?
Trust you?
- 相信你?    - 對!
- Trust you?   - Yes!
我相信過你啊!
I did trust you!
然而你背叛了我!
And you betrayed me!
我曾經每天都在她的雙眸中看到你
I saw you every day in her eyes,
還有在她的笑聲中
and I heard you in her voice when she laughed,
還有當她叫我爸爸時, 我感覺到你在我裡面
and I felt you inside of me when she called me "Daddy."
然後你背叛了我!
And you betrayed me!
你傷透了我的心
You broke my heart.
不
No.
我在萬物當中
I'm in all of it.
我是黑暗同時也是曙光
I'm the darkness and the light,
我是太陽般溫暖同時也是風暴般難以預測
I'm the sunshine and the storm.
你說對了
Yes, you're right.
我存在在她的笑聲中
I was there in her laugh,
但我現在也在你的傷痛之中
but I'm also here now in your pain.
我是萬物的起因
I'm the reason for everything.
我是唯一的"原因"
I am the only "why."
別以為沒了我可以生活, Howard
Don't try and live without me, Howard.
拜託不要
Please don't.
與宏盟集團的協議快要達成了
The deal with Omnicom's almost done.
那Howard那邊呢?
What about Howard?
他們也注意到現在的情況
Well, they're aware of the situation
但我們仍然要證明Howard
but we still have to prove that Howard's ability to vote
沒有投票的能力
is, uh, compromised.
我難以相信變成了這個局面
I can't believe it's come down to this.
對, 但還是得相信
Yeah, well, believe it.
我們星期四有個跟委員會討論Howard能力的會議
We have a competency meeting with the board set for Thursday.
我們來這裡是給你一個解釋的機會
We're here to give you a chance to explain this.
Howard, 影片中你在做甚麼?
Howard, what are you doing in this video?
我不在乎時間
I do not care about time.
這是監禁
This is a prison sentence!
我不想要你的所謂禮物!
I don't want your gift!
你在做甚麼, Howard?
What are you doing, Howard?
因為你拿走了她的時間
Because you took hers.
Howard?
你又要哭嗎?
You gonna cry again?
你不是整天都傷心的嗎?
Aren't you always sad?
這段呢?
What about here?
聽著, 那些甚麼"生命的基本"
Listen. All the "fabric of life" bullshit,
留給跟別人說吧
save that for somebody else.
相信你?
Trust you?
我相信過你啊!
I did trust you!
我把一切托付給你
I committed everything to you
而你背叛了我!
and you betrayed me!
我曾經每天都在她的雙眸中看到你
I saw you every day in her eyes,
還有在她的笑聲中
and I heard you in her voice when she laughed.
我感覺到你在我裡面
And I felt you inside of me...
Howard?
當她叫我爸爸時
...when she called me "Daddy."
Howard?
你傷透了我的心
You broke my heart.
Howard, 我需要你的答覆, 你在跟誰說話?
Howard, I need you to answer me. Who are you shouting at here?
你的陳詞濫調我都聽過了, 我全都明白了
I've heard all of your platitudes. I got them, I know.
不是"誰"
Um, it's not "who."
冥冥中自有主宰
And, "This is all a part of a master plan."
抱歉, 甚麼?
I'm sorry, what?
我明白了
I got it.
Howard, 你說了甚麼?
Howard, did you say something?
我不是在跟人說話
I'm not talking to people.
很明顯, 那你在跟誰說話?
Well, that's obvious. Who are you talking to?
Howard, 你在跟誰說話?
Howard, who are you talking to?
夠了
That's enough. It's enough.
謝謝
Thank you.
我想, 你指出了重點
You made the point, I think.
把它關閉吧
Just turn it off.
你聘請人去跟蹤我?
You hired people to follow me?
去錄影?
Make video?
不, 那不是我們最初的打算
No, that wasn't the initial intention.
對, 我們這樣做了
No, we did.
對
Yeah, we did.
我們除了那還做了很多, Howard
We did a lot more than that, Howard.
Howard, 很抱歉
Howard, I'm so sorry.
我們覺得...
We felt like...
我們不知道還可以做甚麼
We didn't know what else to do.
- Claire.   - 不, 我不能再這樣做了
- Claire.   - No. I can't do this anymore.
我不能, Whit
I can't do this anymore, Whit.
聽著, 我真的...
Listen, I really...
我甚至沒想過那會行得通
I didn't even think that it was gonna work.
- 真的, 坦白說, 我...   - Claire. Claire. Claire.
- Really, honestly, I...  - Claire. Claire. Claire.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
- 好了好了   - Howard...
- All right, all right, all right.   - Howard...
我很顯現地不在狀態
I'm obviously not in the right state of mind.
可能我們所有人都不在狀態
Maybe none of us are.
你以為我沒留意嗎?
You think I haven't noticed?
Claire,
I mean, Claire,
你奉獻了你整生給這公司
you dedicated your entire life to this agency.
你讓我們成為一家人
You made us your family
當你有能力出去闖一番事業的時候
when you could have been starting your own.
還有, 你一直費盡心思
And, uh, you've been absolutely killing yourself,
幫我掩飾
covering for me,
很感謝你
and I appreciate that.
謝謝
Thank you.
還有你, Simon
And, Simon,
你盡力不讓任何人知道
you've done your best to hide it from everyone,
但我知道你的過去
but I know your history.
我懷疑我在將一個無可挽救的局面
And I suspect I'm making an already impossible situation
弄得更糟糕
even worse for you.
我向你保證
I promise you,
我一日還在
as long as I am here,
你的家庭都會得到照料
your family will be cared for.
謝謝
Thank you.
Whit
Whit.
我最好的朋友
Best friend I've ever had.
但我對你很失望
But I'm disappointed in you, man.
我不是指這個
I mean, not for... Not for this.
不是這個
Not for this.
你不需要她的允許才當她的父親
You don't need her permission to be her father.
Allison是你生命中最美好的事
Allison's the best thing you got happening in this world,
人生苦短, 及時行樂
and tomorrow's not promised.
聽到了嗎?
Do you hear me?
你們做了件正確的事
You guys did the right thing.
我想我們的公司繼續運作
I want our agency to survive.
總有些事要繼續吧
Something should.
好了
All right, um...
我會簽署的
I'll sign the papers now.
你同意售賣股份
Your approval of the sale.
另一份呢?
Uh, the other one?
你給了六通電話都要讓我簽署的那份呢?
The one you called me six times to have me sign.
我認為你會一同帶來
Um, I assume you have it here with you.
抱歉, Howord
I am sorry, Howard.
這是件正確的事
This is the right thing.
我告訴你們, 這是件正確的事
I'm telling you, this is the right thing.
抱歉
Excuse me.
第二份文件是甚麼?
What was that second piece of paper?
Howard把他的部份所有權放到他女兒名下的信托基金
Howard put some of his ownership into a trust in his daughter's name.
那只是份法律證書表明她已經不在了
It's just a legal certificate saying she's no longer with us.
我想我需要喝一杯
I think I need a drink.
你還好嗎?
Are you okay?
他們說天堂裡時間的流動
"They say that the time in Heaven
跟我們世界比較起來
"is compared to the blink of an eye
就是一眨眼的工夫
"for us on this Earth.
有時候我會覺得Adam
"Sometimes I think of Adam
正在一遍長滿花草的美麗田園裡奔跑
"running through a beautiful field of wild flowers.
[尋找你的精子捐贈者]
他會是那麼快樂, 忘我地奔跑
"He's so happy, completely caught up in what he's doing.
然後他會回過頭來
"But then he looks back
像他平常跑在我前面時會做的
"like he used to do when he ran ahead of me
在機場或市場, 哪裡都好
"in airports or malls or wherever.
然後他會對著我笑
"And he smiles."
天啊
Jesus.
因為他的一眨眼已經是我的餘生了
"Because the blink of his eye was the rest of my life
而我還在他背後
"and I'm right there behind him."
無論如何, 這是我的第一次
Anyway, it's a first draft.
很美麗的故事
It's beautiful.
真的很美麗
Really beautiful.
還有人想要分享嗎?
Does anybody else wanna say anything?
那好吧, 我想今晚就到此為止了
Okay, I guess that's all for tonight.
謝謝
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
喲
Yo!
簡直不能相信你讓我來到這街區
I can't believe you made me come into this neighborhood
身上還帶著$20,000現金
carrying $20,000 in cash.
你要用來做甚麼?
What are you gonna do with it?
你應該為你的演藝學院儲起來
You should put it aside for acting school.
你很有演技
You were really good.
我要用來買狡詐家藥物
Mmm. I'm gonna use it to buy designer drugs.
那也行
Or that, too.
對
Yeah.
嘿, 你將會是一個好媽媽
Hey, you gonna make a good mom one day.
是嗎?
Yeah?
是的, 那是宣傳單張裡沒說的
Yeah, well, that's pretty much not in the cards.
我以前決定了反對科學
I decided against the science
看來時間終於找上門了
and it seems time finally caught up with me.
以前有個賣書套的人在187號街給了我一本叫美麗新世界的書
There was this dust dealer up on 187th who gave me Brave New World.
那本書讀起來令人樂而忘返
That book turned hours into seconds.
他是我的父親
He was my father.
還有個無家可歸的女人
And there was this homeless woman
在大學高地橋下生活
who lived under the University Heights bridge.
她的名字是Flora
Her name was Flora.
她精神失常, 但她說了最有趣的故事給我
She was batshit crazy, but she told me the greatest stories.
她是我的母親
She was my mother.
聽著, Claire
See, Claire,
你的孩子們不一定要由你生出來
your children don't have to come from you.
他們可以是讓你經過歷練
They go through you.
所以我不會那麼快就考慮跟時間投降
So, I wouldn't consider the battle with time over just yet.
我以為時間不是直線的
I thought time wasn't linear.
我以為它是幻像
I thought it was an illusion.
或者一切都只是廢話而已, Claire
Maybe that was just bullshit, Claire.
或者那只是演戲
Maybe that was just acting.
- 嗨, Allison   - 我們快走吧
- Hey, Allison.   - Come on, let's go.
別這樣, Allison!
Oh. Come on. Allison!
我晚點跟你們會面
I'll meet you guys there.
你知道我不想跟你說話
I don't wanna talk to you. You know that.
別煩我
Leave me alone.
不, 我永遠不會留下你
No. I won't leave you alone.
- 不會嗎?   - 不會
- No?   - No.
我知道你在生我的氣, 那很正常
I know you're angry at me, and that's okay.
我承受得到
I can take it.
但我們需要好好談談, 因為那就是家人會做的事
But we gotta talk about it
because that's what you do in a family.
所以我每天都會來並在你的朋友面前讓你顯得尷尬
So I'm gonna come here every day
and embarrass you in front of your friends
直到你跟我說話為止
until you talk to me.
所以你打算跟蹤我?
So you're gonna stalk me?
對, 基本上是
Well... Yes, basically.
那如果我申請限制令呢?
Well, what if I get a restraining order?
我不認為你有能力可以做到
Well, I don't think you're gonna be able to do that.
我會讓媽媽替我付錢
Well, I'll get Mom to pay for it.
跟你說下, 它們是免費的
Well, for your information, they're free.
那我會讓你替我付錢
Well, then I'll get you to pay for it.
我真的很愛你
I really love you.
媽媽說你令那個字變質了
Mom says you butcher that word.
不在我跟你說的時候
Not when I say it to you.
聽著
Look...
我沒能力帶著你飛到緬因州吃午餐
I can't fly you to Maine for lunch
或者用駕著特斯拉來接你
or get you picked up in a Tesla
或者讓你到Anna Wintour旗下實習 [時尚雜誌編輯]
and take you to your internship with Anna Wintour
或者他們在這街區會做的事
or whatever the hell they do in this neighborhood.
但我想我們可以坐在公園的長椅上
But I think that you and me can sit on a park bench
說說笑, 享受一段美好時光
and tell jokes and have a pretty good time.
我不能相信你會跟蹤我
I can't believe you're gonna stalk me.
但...
But, um...
只是說下, 明天只有半天課
Just so you know, tomorrow's a half-day.
那我明天也會在這裡
Well, I'll be here then.
嗨
Hey.
你的
Here you are.
我等了別人給我的肯定很久了
I've been waiting a long time for my moment for validation,
這就是我要的
and this was it.
一位在角落不起眼, 也不拍掌的觀眾
An audience of one, in secret, with no applause.
我跟我的妻子說了
I told my wife.
那她怎樣反應?
Oh, how did it go?
她早就知道了
She knew.
她在做準備了
She's getting ready for it.
當我還年輕時, 我經常想
You know, when I was younger, I used to think,
你真的想活到一百歲嗎?
you really wanna live to be 100 years old?
像乾癟了的葡萄乾一樣
You know, like a shriveled up raisin.
而我現在會給的答覆是
And the answer to that now
對
is yes.
因為我的兒子將會是70歲
Because my son would be 70,
他的兒子會是40歲
his son would be 40,
他的兒子會是10
and his son would be 10.
而我就能成為那個人
And I would be the man, you know.
老爸的角色
Pops.
真想成為啊
Could get used to that, you know.
再見, 老爸
See you around, Pops.
我真想去看你的話劇
I wish I could be here to see the play.
不, 那話劇經過是次早就沒了
Oh, no, no. The play is dead after all this.
但誰知道呢
But you never know,
沒甚麼是死的, 如果以正確的角度去看的話
nothing's ever really dead if you look at it right.
嗨
Hey.
今晚是平安夜
Uh, it's Christmas Eve.
而你只獨身一人
And you're alone.
我自願的
By choice.
我可以破壞你獨處的時間嗎?
Can I ruin that?
[最好的媽媽]
你剛才在哭
You've been crying.
我剛才在看我為我女兒拍的影片
I was watching a video I took of my daughter.
她在跟她的父親跳舞
She's dancing with her father in it.
我能給你看嗎, Howard?
Can I show it to you, Howard?
我女兒叫Olivia
My daughter's name was Olivia.
她因為一種罕有的腦癌而過世
She died of a rare form of brain cancer
叫膠質母細胞瘤
known as Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或簡稱GBM
or GBM for short.
她當時六歲
She was six years old.
你的女兒叫甚麼, Howard?
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
如果我們可以重新相遇一次就好了
"If only we could be strangers again."
你的女兒叫甚麼, Howard?
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
我不能...
I can't.
I... I can't.
轉快點!
Swing me faster!
快點快點, 爸爸!
Faster, Daddy! Faster!
Howard...
我是隻小鳥
I feel like a bird.
說出她的名字
Say her name.
她叫甚麼?
What was her name?
Olivia.
她叫Olivia
Her name was Olivia.
她怎過身的?
How did she die?
她患了一種叫膠質母細胞瘤的罕有癌症
She had a rare form of cancer called Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或簡稱GBM
or GBM for short.
她當時才六歲
She was only six years old.
她叫Olivia
Her name was Olivia.
她患了一種叫膠質母細胞瘤的罕有癌症
She had a rare form of cancer called Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或簡稱GBM
or GBM for short.
她當時才六歲
She was only six years old.
我們寶貝的名字叫Olivia
Our baby's name was Olivia.
她當時才六歲
She was only six years old.
你們在做甚麼?
What are you guys doing?
你準備好了嗎?
You ready? You ready?
去吧!
Go, go!
現在我們由頭再做一次
Now we start all over again.
你準備好了嗎?
You ready?
我們由頭再做一次
We start all over again.
你要失去一個親人嗎?
Are you losing somebody?
甚麼?
I'm sorry?
你要失去誰?
Who are you losing?
我的女兒
Um, my daughter.
記著留意附屬的美麗
Just make sure you notice the collateral beauty.